kumc.edu 2018-11-21

# University of Kansas Medical Center Privacy Statement

## Online Privacy

The University of Kansas Medical Center ("KUMC") respects the privacy of visitors to our website.

Activity data is collected throughout the website. This data includes the visitor's subdomain, browser version, operating system, and which pages are accessed. Such information is gathered for statistical purposes but may be reviewed in the course of site maintenance, system troubleshooting, or security management. Visitors to the site are not personally identified in connection with the collection or use of the above statistics.

#### Information Collected and Stored Automatically

If you visit our site to read or download information, we may collect and store the following information about your visit:

  1. The name of the Internet domain (for example, "xcompany.com" if you use a private Internet access account, or "yourschool.edu" if you are connecting from a university's domain) and the IP address (a number automatically assigned to your computer when you are using the Internet) from which you access our site;
  2. The type of browser and operating system used to access our site;
  3. The date and time you access our site;
  4. The Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our site; and
  5. The pages you visit and the information you request.

This information is primarily collected for statistical analysis and technical improvements to the site. This computer system uses software programs to create summary statistics, which may be used for such purposes as assessing what information is of most and least interest, determining technical design specifications, and identifying system performance or problem areas. When required by law or security related necessity, we may take additional steps to identify you based on collected information.

#### Web Use by Children

This website is not directed to anyone under the age of 13. The website does not knowingly collect or solicit information from anyone under the age of 13. In the event that we learn that we have gathered information from anyone under the age of 13 without consent of a parent or guardian, we will delete the information as soon as possible.

#### Cookies

"Cookies" are small bits of text which are either used for the duration of a session ("session cookies"), or saved on a user's hard drive in order to identify that user, or information about that user, the next time the user logs on to a website ("persistent cookies").

Certain KU Medical Center sites solicit personal information when necessary to provide specific services, such as fulfilling library requests. Collection of confidential information, via such sites, such as credit card numbers and patient information, use SSL (secure socket layers) to safeguard your personal data against interception during transmission. All of the data collected via these websites is confidential and accessible only to employees of the University. At no time will the University sell or distribute personal information to a third party.

We reserve the right to update or change our Privacy Statement at any time and encourage you to check this Privacy Statement periodically. Your continued use of KU Medical Center websites after we post any modifications to the Privacy Statement will constitute your acknowledgment of the modifications and your consent to abide and be bound by the modified Privacy Statement.

Questions regarding this privacy statement or the practices of this site may be submitted to [amitchell5@kumc.edu](http://www.kumc.edu/amitchell5@kumc.edu "email KUMC privacy director").

This Statement was last updated on May 25, 2018.

## Notice of Privacy Practices for Patients at KU Medical Center

Our  **[Notice of Privacy Practices](http://www.kumc.edu/Documents/hipaa/KUMCNoticeofPrivacyPractices.pdf)** (260KB [Acrobat](http://www.adobe.com/products/acrobat/readermain.html) file) details the way in which medical information about you may be used and disclosed and how you can get access to this information.

Last modified: Jul 26, 2018
